靠  太倒霉了吧  兄台
Wow! Bummer, dude.
你有台时光机
You have a time machine?
却把自己传送到这间破烂餐厅
And somehow, it got programmed to this crap diner?
我承认  我是挺迷蒸汽朋克的
I must admit, I am quite taken with steampunk.
蒸汽朋克啊  我记得啊
Oh, steampunk, right. I remember that trend.
那玩意儿在2000年的
It happened for, like, ten seconds
"你当我白痴啊"时代流行过十秒钟
back in 2000 and-are-you-kidding-me?
兄台  说真的  坐在公共场合里
Dude, seriously, you're sitting in a public place
在老式打字机上敲敲打打
tap-tap-tapping on an oldie typewriter?
你以为你谁啊
What are you?
超装逼联盟的参赛选手吗
In the league of extraordinarily pretentious gentlemen?
你说话有点太咄咄逼人了吧
Aren't you being a little aggressive?
没错
Yup.
我们"当代人"都这么说话
That's how people are here in the present where we live.
你别误会我
But don't get me wrong.
我也想要穿梭时空呢
I'd like to go back in time, too.
去阻止911或那乱"射"在我鞋上的变态
Maybe stop 9/11 or that creep who had sex on my shoe,
可我没办法啊
but I can't.
什么当代啊  瞧你那身制服
Present? Where's that uniform from?
1998年买的吗
From like, 1998?
再乱说
Oh, stop, or I'm going to have
我就要用我的威森枪崩了你啦
to shoot you with a Smith & Wesson
枪就藏在我的灯笼裤里哦
I'm currently packing in my bloomers.
吾去给汝拿份菜单吧
I'll go get thee a menu, my good man.
大伙们  注意啦
Attention, everyone.
我跟麦克斯有深夜小礼物要给你们
Max and I have a little late-night treat for you.
别用这种兴奋的语气说好吗
Don't say it all excited like that.
你又不是给毒品  厄尔会失望得发火的
Now when it's not drugs, Earl's going to be pissed.
你们获邀参加万分重要的
You are invited to a very important taste-test
麦克斯自制小蛋糕品尝会
of Max's homemade cupcakes.
好的  不过我只吃一个哦
Okay, but I will have only one.
我一有小肚腩  单身女郎会叫我弥勒佛
When I get a tummy, single ladies call me Buddha
还摸我肚皮求好运
and rub me for luck.
我也得小心
I gotta watch out, too.
上次我回家前  吃了一个麦克斯的
Last time I had Max's chocolate espresso cupcake
黑咖啡小蛋糕
just before going home,
结果早上5点都睡不着
I was awake till 5:00 A.M.,
手洗了一夜的丁字裤
hand washing all my thongs.
丁字裤啊  你个小坏蛋
Thongs? Earl, you devil.
别看我头顶花白  白发胜雪
That's right, just because there's snow on the roof
裤裆里还是龙精虎猛  翻江倒海呢
doesn't mean there's not swing in the sling.
卡洛琳  亲爱的  你能去我座位
Oh, Caroline, darling. Can you go back over there?
帮我拿赛马报吗
I forgot my racing form.
赛马啊  害我好想念栗宝
Oh, horse racing? It reminds me of Chestnut.
麦克斯  小栗宝
Max... Chestnut.
你装个屁哭脸啊
What's with the sad face?
你的马就住在附近的豪华马厩
Your horse is living it up at a fancy stable nearby.
又不是住在天国的种马场
Not gone to the great stud farm in the sky.
有人提到"种马场"吗
Did someone say "stud farm"?
我的精每0.9升10块  包生男的15块
My fee is $10 a quart or $15 if you want a boy.
不错啊
Wow.
看来你已经走出分手的阴霾了
You bounced back from your Sophie breakup pretty quick.
我们不是真分手
It was not a real breakup.
她很快又会回到我身边
I will have her very soon again.
现阶段  我就淡定地躲在草丛
Right now, I lay low and wait in bushes
如同盯上猎物的猎豹
like determined jungle cat.
是盯上猎物的强奸犯吧
Or a rapist.
给  赛马报
Racing forms, here you go.
厄尔  找机会
Earl, maybe some time
你也带我去马场吧
you will take me out to the track with you.
我以前在韩国时  常常骑马呢
I used to ride horses all the time in Korea.
超市外那种一块钱一次的电动小马吗
The mechanical ones for a quarter in front of supermarkets?
麦克斯  我可是很厉害的骑师
Actually, Max, I'm a very good rider.
我受过赛马骑师的训练呢
In fact, I was training to be a jockey
可惜我身高不够高
but was too short.
矮到当不了骑师吗
Too short to be a jockey?
这也太悲催了吧  阿憨
That's a hard hit, my man.
阿憨  真没想到你也爱马
Han, I had no idea you loved horses, too.
怎么都没听你提过啊
Why didn't you ever say anything?
那你怎么不问问我有什么兴趣呢
Well, why didn't you ever ask about any of my interests?
我来告诉你原因
I'll tell you why.
因为你开口闭口永远都是
Because all you ever talk about is
"我们的小蛋糕生意如何如何"
"our cupcake business, our cupcake business."
你这张光盘就没别的曲子了吗
Doesn't your CD have other tracks?
话说  我们的小蛋糕生意
Anyway, our cupcake business
明天有场十分重要的会面呢
has a very important meeting tomorrow
要去见派对大师  保罗·普拉特
with Paul Platt, the party planner.
我也认识个派对大师
I know a party planner, too.
他在墨西哥独立日时
He sells J.Lo. and Salma Hayek pinatas
在街上卖明星头像的彩陶罐
off back of truck for Cinco de Mayo.
我要一个海耶克头像的罐子
Awesome. Put me down for a Hayek.
有额外空间  装糖方便
More storage space for candy.
我们要见的可是曼哈顿的大红人
Well, our party planner is the it guy in Manhattan.
明天我要跟麦克斯带小蛋糕
And tomorrow, Max and I are doing
去他办公室给他品尝
a tasting for him at his office.
怎么有人能矮到不能当马师啊
How can someone be too short to be a jockey?
马师不就得是矮子吗
Isn't that the whole point?
麦克斯  你没事吧
Are you all right, Max?
我尽快赶来了
I got here as fast as I could.
卡洛琳发短信叫我快来
Caroline texted me to hurry over
说你不知道自己怀孕
because you didn't know you were pregnant,
还准备要在厕所生孩子
and you were giving birth over toilet.
我抓着马桶吸就冲来了
So I grabbed my plunger and ran!
太夸张了吧  我没发过这短信啊
That is insane. I never texted that.
我发的  我刚偷用了你的手机
No, I did, when I stole your phone.
我要拐苏菲过来得有理由嘛
I needed a reason to get Sophie over here.
我不敢相信她会信你的屁话
I can't believe she believed it.
麦克斯  在厕所里生娃
Oh, come on, Max. Giving birth over toilet?
十足你的风格
That is very you.
苏菲  既然你都来了  坐吧
Now that you are here, Sophie, sit.
我想跟你说一件重要的事
I want to tell you something important.
你就算了吧
Well, you can forget that.
我才不会留下来呢
There's no way I'm going to stay.
有小蛋糕派对啊
A cupcake party?
这一个上面还有椒盐卷饼呢
Oh, look, and this one even has a pretzel in it.
那是我们的"咸配香料"口味
Yup, that's our "salty n' spice"
给喜爱新奇口味的顾客
for our more adventurous customers.
而保守的白人顾客呢
Also for the uptight white people,
我们也做了非常传统的香草口味
we have the very, very vanilla
毫无意外...这也是我最爱的口味
which is... big surprise... my favorite.
这是酒混面粉加枫蜜培根的
And this is our beer-batter maple bacon
特制春假小蛋糕
spring break cupcake.
给瘾君子的  比如我的最爱啦
That's for stoners, and big surprise, my favorite.
我也有大消息
Well, I have some big news
想要跟在座的各位分享
I want to share with you all as well.
苏菲  也就是坐在那里的高贵仕女
Sophie, that classy lady right over there...
我喜欢这个口味
Mm, I like this one.
她不久前刚与我分手
She recently broke it off with me
理由是  她想跟一个有梦想
because she wanted to be with a man
有冲劲的男人在一起
who had a dream and a drive.
所以我买了台"冲劲"
So I have bought a drive...
一台林肯豪华加长轿车
A Lincoln town car.
没错  我现在当司机还有新标语
Yes, I have a new car service and slogan:
"放松坐好  你不喊停  我绝不停下"
"lie back and I will ride you till you tell me to stop."
奥列格  所以你现在要当轿车司机
So, Oleg, you now have a town car business?
而苏菲  你总是租加长轿车
And Sophie, you rent town cars all the time.
那又如何
Oh, oh, please.
我也喜欢吃披萨
I mean, I love pizza, too,
难道我还得嫁给棒约翰的约翰先生吗
but that doesn't mean I have to marry PaPa John.
我刚在想  你可能会对我车上那面
I was just thinking, you might want to come out back
会发亮的化妆镜有兴趣呢
and take a look at the light-up makeup mirror on visors.
会发亮的化妆镜
Light-up makeup mirror?
感觉挺有意思啊
Oh, I might be interested.
不过我不要单独跟你去
But not just you and I.
阿憨也一起来吧
Han will come as well.
终于啊  有人邀请阿憨一起去玩
Finally! Han is getting invited to something.
别人只邀我加入网站过
Other than LinkedIn.
品尝会就先到这里吧  不过没事
So much for the taste test. It's fine.
我知道怎么做对我们的小蛋糕生意最好
I know what's best for our cupcake business.
我的确是很常提到呢
I do say that a lot,
但我觉得也挺迷人的
but I think it's kind of charming.
我去拿我们的外套吧
I'll go get our coats.
你看你
Mm, mm, mm. Look at you.
我不得不说  你的变化非常大
I must say, I'm impressed with how far you've come.
烤坏了几千个小蛋糕
Well, you burn a few thousand cupcakes,
总会熟能生巧的嘛
you're bound to get better.
不只是烤蛋糕技术啊  麦克斯
Not just the cupcakes, Max.
你人也成长了很多
Look how far you've come.
想当年  你只是个打工混日子
When I think of that girl who came in here
过一天是一天的人
just looking to get by...
瞧你现在
Hey, and check you out now.
要去曼哈顿跟大人物面谈了  厉害啊
Big, fancy meeting in Manhattan. Lordy lord!
-厄尔  只是小面谈啦  -或许吧
- It's only a meeting, Earl. - Maybe.
可如果你是一匹赛马
But if you were one of these horses,
我愿把毕生积蓄压在你身上呢
I'd put all of my money on you, Max.
保罗·普拉特派对公司  请稍等
Paul Platt parties. Please hold.
可怜的娃啊
Poor kid.
如果我是他  我就会对人说
If I had that job, I'd be asking someone
请拿枪毙了我吧
to please hold a gun to my head.
能为保罗·普拉特工作  他一定很兴奋
He's probably excited to be working for Paul Platt.
看看这些杂志
Look at all these magazines
都称他是下一代的玛莎·斯图尔特
calling him the next Martha Stewart.
有一天  杂志也会有我们的专题的
Someday, we'll have articles about us.
还配上我们俩站在
You know, pictures of you and me
我们别墅外的照片
standing outside our country home.
等等
Hold on.
我们有钱后还得一起住啊
We're rich and still living together?
好了  她要走了  轮到我们了
Okay, she's leaving. This is us.
是该到我们了
About time.
坐等好久  我屁股都睡着了
Been sitting here so long my ass is asleep,
但我是不会夹着屁股逃跑的
which kind of goes against my theory that it won't quit.
保罗还有点事  请稍等
Hi, Paul's going to be a little longer.
没关系  不过还...
It's fine. It's just how much...
保罗·普拉特派对公司  请稍等
Paul Platt parties, please hold.
-保罗·普拉特派对公司  -还得等...
- Paul Platt parties... - How much longer...
-请稍等  -我们还是他们
- Please hold. - Me or them?
坐得姐屁股发麻
I got the ass pins and needles.
-麦克斯  -干嘛  反正没轮到我们
- Max. - What? We're on hold.
请坐吧  再稍等五分钟
Have a seat. Five more minutes.
保罗·普拉特派对公司
Paul Platt parties.
派对公司墙上挂写着派对的画
The word "Party" at a party planner's?
脱裤子放屁嘛
Little obvious.
跟我挂一幅"孤独终老"一样多余
Like me having art that says "will die alone."
等等
Wait.
不会吧  这是强尼画的
I think this is Johnny's art. No way.
当然不会  强尼只是小角色
"No way" is right. Johnny's a nobody.
保罗·普拉特才不屑挂强尼的画呢
Paul Platt wouldn't have a framed "Johnny" in his office.
你看这签名  写着电子图档哥呢
Look, signed "Jpeg." That's his tag.
这画谁画的啊
Yo, what's the deal with this art?
一个街头艺术家
It's a street artist.
最近还挺火热的
Everyone's getting really into him now.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
几个月前他也想跟我"搞"得火热呢
He was trying to get into me a few months ago.
其实是有故事的啦
It was more emotional than that.
他搞外遇来找她
He cheated on his girlfriend with her
后来又把她甩了
and then blew her off.
这事情伤我们挺深的
It was really hard for us.
靠  我拍屁股不适当
And you thought me slapping my ass
你说这些话就适当啊
in front of him was inappropriate?
-强尼成功啦  -恭喜他
- Wow, Johnny made it. - Well, good for him.
他平步青云  我们也快了
He's making it, we're making it...
我们快成功个屁
We're making it?
我还得用油性笔给我的靴子补色
I magic-markered over the scuffs on my boot,
而且我们连穷人版
and we can't even get past
约翰·库萨克这一关都过不去
the poor man's John Cusack over there.
麦克斯  我们成功在望
Max, we are making it.
我们度过了这么多难关
We've come a long way.
我们都没用星巴克餐巾纸
We haven't used Starbucks napkins
当厕纸好久了
for toilet paper in months.
你看  我们现在的进度
And now, look where we are.
到现在  居然能有机会见保罗·普拉特
We've got a meeting with Paul Platt.
快说  "我们成功在望"
Say it, "we're making it."
我是认真的  你得说出口
I'm serious. Say it, Max.
我们成功在望
We are making it.
好啦  我们成功在望
Okay, we're making it.
-卡洛琳·钱宁  -到我们了
- Caroline channing. - This is us!
-这个嘛...  -又怎么了  再等五分钟吗
- Ahh. - What, five more minutes?
突然有要事  改约周一下午4点了
Monday at 4:00. Something came up.
好吧  周一下午4点
Oh, okay. Well, Monday at 4:00.
他不会见我们了  对吧
There's no Monday at 4:00.
他说了周一下午4点  没骗人吧
He said Monday at 4:00. Monday at 4:00, right?
当然没有  周一下午4点见
Absolutely. Monday at 4:00.
他不会见你们了
There is no Monday at 4:00.
我有点糊涂了 他到底要不要见我们呀
I'm confused. Is there a Monday at 4:00?
白纸黑字写着  周一下午4点  保罗等不及了
In the books, Monday at 4:00. Paul can't wait.
他压根没有要见你们
There is no Monday at 4:00.
我搞糊涂了  我们是来还是不来啊
I don't understand. Are we coming in Monday at 4:00?
当然来啊  保罗很喜欢你们
Absolutely. Paul's a big fan.
周一别来了
Don't come in on Monday.
你能解释一下到底怎么了吗
Can you please tell me what's going on?
最近新闻在报导你老爸被转移到
See, it's this news about your father being moved
舒坦的高智慧罪犯监狱
to a cushy white collar prison this week.
保罗不敢跟叫"钱宁"的人扯上关系
Paul can't have anything to do with someone named Channing,
毕竟全市都在不爽"钱宁"呢
'cause everyone in New York is pissed.
你看  我的过去阴魂不散
Look at all that. It never stops.
我还得再受多少折磨啊
How much more of this do I have to take?
所以我们周一见吧
So we'll see you on Monday!
别来了
Don't come.
靠  早知道不叫我屁股起床了
I woke my ass up for this?
麦克斯  小蛋糕太好吃了
Mmm. This was delicious, Max.
给你20块吧  不用找钱了
Here's a $20. Keep the change.
苏菲  你这是干嘛
What are you doing, Sophie?
我不会收你小蛋糕钱的
You don't pay for the cupcakes.
为了生意而收下吧
No, take it for your business.
你们跟派对大师的面谈失败后
Ever since your big party planner meeting went bust,
我就一直很担心你们
I was worried that you two girls
会办一个自杀姐妹会
might form a joint suicide pact.
放心  我们没那种组织力
Nah, we're not that organized.
卡洛琳心情如何
So how's Caroline today?
比我想象中的好多了
She's handling it all better than I thought.
她去见她爸爸的代表律师了
She's with her father's lawyer right now,
想趁她老爸移监前
trying to figure out the best time for her
找出一个好时机去探访他
to go out to the prison to see him before he's moved.
是我的新手机
Oh, that is my new phone.
你的基佬娃娃上还粘了支手机呢
You know there's a phone stuck to that gay Furby, right?
这是我去14街上  我最爱的店买来的呢
Yes, this is from my favorite store on 14th street,
店名叫"人造钻石"
Rhinestoned.
是我司机发来的短信
Oh, it's just a text from my driver.
他在楼下等了
He's waiting out front.
直接叫奥列格上来不就好了吗
Why don't you just invite Oleg inside?
我还不确定他是否够格进来
I'm not sure yet he deserves to come inside.
据我所知  他不是早够格"进入"了吗
Well, from what I heard, he's already come inside.
麦克斯  我就爱听你说荤段子
Oh, Max, I love it when you're dirty!
怎么样了
Hey, how'd it go?
根据我父亲的律师所说
Well, according to my father's lawyer,
监狱被太多媒体包围
the prison is surrounded by so much press
老爸不想我出现
that daddy doesn't want me to come out there
然后被媒体再度生吞活剥
and be exploited all over again.
为啥就没有其他大新闻了啊
Why is he still the only news story out there?
别气  好歹今天
Well, the good news is,
你的头发超闪闪动人啊
your hair is especially shiny today.
真的吗  谢了  苏菲
It is? Thanks, Sophie.
听完就别想着自杀了哦
So try not to kill yourself.
我在车上读这些信时  都没跑去死
Well, if I didn't kill myself reading these in the car,
现在也不会了
I won't.
怒骂信
Hate mail.
这些全都寄到了我以前的邮箱
It was being held at my old P.O. Box.
我父亲的律师帮我收的信
My father's lawyer picked it up for me.
他何不直接扁你一拳就算了
Why didn't he just punch you in the face and call it a day?
对啊  这跟《34街的奇迹》的结局差不多
I know, it's like the end of Miracle on 34th street,
差别只是  大家都叫我贱货
only everyone's calling me a bitch.
也不是大家都骂你贱货的吧
Oh, come on, not everyone is calling you a bitch.
"贱货你好  我恨你"
"Dear bitch, I hate you."
"哪天让我在街上见到你  我一定...
"If I ever see you on the street, I will..."
会跟你握手  然后祝福你平安
shake your hand and wish you well,
希望你能雨过天晴"
as you have been through so very much.
信上才不是这么写呢
That is not what that says.
也是有可能啊
It might be.
他这血书字迹太潦草
It's hard to read his actual words,
什么内容都有可能啊
as they are written in blood.
好华丽的信封  这不是怒骂信啊
Oh, look how fancy. This is not hate mail.
是邀请参加大都会博物馆的年度晚会
No, this is invitation to Metropolitan Museum annual gala.
是吗
It is?
这是我在纽约最爱的社交活动了
This is my favorite social event in all of New York.
18岁那年起  我每年都去了
I've gone every year since I was 18.
这是在美术博物馆里的时尚舞会
It's a fashion ball at the museum of art...
我知道那是干嘛的
Yeah, I know what it is.
-我去年去当过服务生呢  -麦克斯  太巧了吧
- I catered it last year. - Max, how weird.
没准去年我们就再同一个房间里
We were probably right in the very same room.
那我很可能有往你饮料吐过口水哦
Then there's a good chance I spit in your drink.
也不见得  除非你当时又霸道又烦人
Not really, unless you were acting all prissy and demanding.
那还真有可能给饮料吐过口水
There's a good chance you spit in my drink.
你们看  还是有好消息的
Well, see? This is happy news.
我是想去啊  可我去不了
No, as much as I want to, I can't go.
大家都恨我
Everybody hates me.
更惨的是  我没礼服穿
And much worse, I have nothing to wear,
要当过街老鼠  也要当最美的老鼠
and if you're gonna be hated, you better look damn good.
我放弃  这邀请函是压倒我的最后一根稻草
I give up. That invitation finally broke me.
你干嘛把床拉下来啊
Why are you pulling down your bed?
因为我没有房门可以让我甩
Because I don't have a door to slam.
我连门都没有
Hell, I don't even have a door!
什么东西都没了  麦克斯
Everything's been taken away, Max...
亿万家产  工作
My fortune, my business career,
亲朋好友  跟我最爱的小马
my social life, my sweet, sweet horse.
你还是去睡吧  你心情不好
Okay, take a nap. You're upset.
你有心情不好的理由
You have a good reason to be.
而且不止一个哟
A good reason?
她有足足2 300个理由呢
I say she has 200, 300 good reasons.
你也来读读
I mean, read these.
这些简直是死亡催命符
These are like letters to the devil.
我要上床  从此长赖不起
I'm just going to get in there and never get out.
麦克斯  把我合上去  夹进墙吧
Close it up, Max. Put me in the wall.
没办法  你躺在上面时合不上去
No, it's really hard to close it when you're in there.
我早试过了
I've tried.
我知道现在跟你以前相比
Look, I know it's not even remotely close
有着天壤之别
to what you had before,
可我们还有小蛋糕生意啊
but we do have our cupcake business
还有紫色烤箱  还有922块的开店基金
and our purple stove, and we do have $922.
我们成功在望
And we're gonna make it.
夹  爆  我
Wall me.
你不就需要一个大派对让你崭露头角嘛
Come on, all you need is a big, glamorous party.
你看邀请名单上的名流
I mean, look at all the celebrities that are on the list
玛莎·斯图尔特
Martha Stewart,
贾斯丁·汀布莱克
Justin Timberlake...
休·杰克曼
Ooh, Hugh Jackman!
我都喜欢叫他巨根·杰克曼
Oh, I like to call him "Huge" Jackman,
因为我猜他一定有"巨根"
because I bet he has a big penis.
夹  爆  我
Wall me.
谢谢啦
Thank you, sir.
欢迎回家啊  栗宝
Welcome home, buddy.
如你所见到的  我们还没弄好泳池
As you can see, we haven't put the pool in yet.
以后会弄的
We'll get to it.
树  烤炉  铲子  你的老朋友们都在
Tree, grill, shovel... usual cast of characters.
我现在就带你去见她吧
Now, I am going to take you in to her,
不过我先警告你
but I should warn you.
她两天没下床了
She hasn't been out of bed for two days,
她那两天没刷过牙的嘴  口气很惊人的
and that means no tooth brushing and it's bad up in there.
我猜你们马的嗅觉应该很好
I'm pretty sure horses have a keen sense of smell,
所以你还是做好心理准备
so just be prepared.
我也很想你啊  栗宝
I missed you, too.
麦克斯  我在睡觉呢  脱鞋好吗
Max, I'm trying to sleep. Take your boots off.
卡洛琳  我有东西要给你看哦
Caroline, I have something for you.
此人已死  有事烧纸
Go away. I'm dead.
天啊  你还嫌我嘴臭
Jeez, and you said my breath was bad.
你有个访客哦  你很爱他呢
You have a visitor, someone you love.
栗宝  栗宝  宝贝你来啦
Chestnut! Chestnut, hi, baby, hi.
他怎么来的
How did he get here?
我去找了琵琪  跟她说
I went to Peach and told her
人命关天
it was a matter of life and death
必须得把栗宝带回来
and we had to have him back.
她就这么让你把他带走啊
And what, she just gave him back to you?
我还得同意我这一生每周都得去
Well, I did have to agree to come back and babysit
照看她的小孩一天
one day a week for the rest of my life,
随便啦  反正栗宝回来啦
but hell, Chestnut's home.
麦克斯  谢谢你  你让我重获新生
Max, thank you so much. You brought me back to life.
求你了  别对我吐气好吗
Oh, my God, don't exhale on me.
你的口气跟吃过大便似地
Your breath is like you went down on a brussels sprout.
把你的头转走
Tip your head that way.
栗宝  栗宝
Chestnut, Chestnut.
也别对他吐气好吗
Don't breathe on him either!
他的鼻子占了头大半  你想熏死他啊
His whole head is a nose. He can't handle that.
栗宝回家了
Chestnut home.
厄尔  好久不见啊
Hey, Earl. Long time, no see.
哎哟  是强尼啊
Well, well, well, Johnny.
传说中的那位街头画家
If it isn't the famous street artist.
也没到传说中啦
Well, I'm hardly famous.
没错
You got that right.
我单纯是想讽刺你
My remark was laced with sarcasm.
能告诉麦克斯我来了吗
Can you tell Max I'm here?
不好说  你还是脚踏两船吗
That depends. Are you still a two-timing bum?
那是他的乳名  直呼不得
That's his name, don't wear it out.
好久不见啊  小猛女
Hiya, slugger.
能帮我让厄尔消停消停吗
Can you do me a favor and call Earl off?
虽然我也勤于锻炼
I may be on day six of my p90x,
但我是打不过他这种强大选手的
but I'm in no shape to take on a heavyweight like him.
没事了  厄尔
It's okay, Earl, we're cool.
他在姐身后吃尘呢
Well, I am. He's just riding my fumes.
你管哪区呢
So, uh, where's your section?
-吧台  -老样子啊  老样子
- Counter. - Hm, same ol', same ol'.
强尼来餐厅了
Johnny's in the diner.
他来干嘛啊  肯定不是来吃东西
Why is he here? It can't be to eat.
人家成功了  只吃成功人士的食物
He's "made it." He eats "made it food" now.
他明显是来找你的
Well, obviously, he's here to see you.
不然就是他赢了"纽约最佳爱情骗子奖"
Or else he won the award for biggest lying jerk in New York,
餐厅是他巡回的第一站
and this is the first stop on his press tour.
我不知道他来干嘛
Well, I don't know why he's here,
不过你最后还是陪着我吧
but you better come with me.
他帅气逼人  我完全没听进
He looks really good, so I'm not listening
他帅唇吐出的任何一句话
to a thing coming out of his pretty mouth.
本来想问你今天有什么特餐
Well, I was gonna ask what the specials were,
不过还是算了  我能就点一个
but you know what? Can I actually just get
麦克斯自制小蛋糕吗
one of Max's homemade cupcakes?
-行啊  什么口味  -给我个惊喜
- Okay, which flavor? - Surprise me.
跟你有女朋友一样让麦克斯"惊喜"吗
Kind of like how you surprised her with your girlfriend?
好吧  我知道你们的意思了
Okay, I'm starting to get a vibe here,
我也是为了这事而来  我心有愧疚
and that's why I came in, because I feel bad,
来为我们的不欢而散
the way things went down between us,
画下句点  和你道别
and I came to say good-bye
我很快就要搬走了
because I'm moving.
搬走  搬去哪里啊
Oh, moving. To where?
-曼哈顿  -曼哈顿啊
- Manhattan. - Manhattan?
搬去那里还道个屁别啊
That hardly calls for a good-bye speech.
离得很近好吗
It's over there.
但搬过去就是两个世界了
Yeah, I know, but it's a big change for me,
我们将不再是
and we're not going to be rolling
一个圈子的人
in the same circles anymore,
我也要去那边  结婚了
and I'm getting married... over there.
起码你跟你那女朋友修成正果了
Well, at least you and your girlfriend worked it out.
其实我们分手了
Actually, we broke up.
我是要跟几个月前认识的另一个女人结婚
This is someone I met a couple months ago.
我刚只读他的唇了
I was only watching his lips,
但他刚才说的话我没看错吧
but did they just say what I think they said?
给  你要的小蛋糕  5块钱
Well, there's your cupcake. That'll be $5.
没错  涨价了  我们现在也是成功人士了
The price has gone up. Yeah, we're successful now.
我们可能要跟家政女皇合作了呢
In fact, we may be working with Martha Stewart.
卡洛琳以前跟她有些关系
Caroline knows her from, you know, before.
卡洛琳获邀去博物馆的年度晚会
We're gonna talk it over with her the met gala ball
我们会在那里跟她详谈
at that Caroline got invited to.
玛莎是委员会的人  而卡洛琳也年年出席
Martha's on the committee. Caroline goes every year.
小事一桩啦
Not a big deal.
虽然我是第一次  不过也没啥啦
My first time. Not a big deal either.
说实在的  全都没什么嘛
In fact, none of it's a big deal,
不过就是两个成功在望的姑娘
just two girls who are making it
因为个性帅气  所以留在布鲁克林奋斗嘛
but who choose to stay in Brooklyn 'cause we're cool.
恭喜你啊  麦克斯  真心恭喜
That's awesome, Max. That's awesome.
你知道吗  每当我想起你时
It's just funny, because whenever I think of you,
总是浮现你在这餐厅穿着制服的画面
I think of you in this diner in that uniform.
不是贬低你哦
In a good way.
你要收钱吗
You want money now?
是啊  在商言商嘛
Yeah. It's business.
我们又不是在一起或什么的
It's not like we had a relationship or anything.
其实你还是付给卡洛琳吧
In fact, you can pay Caroline.
她管账  我管创作
She's the money. I'm the artist.
我的创作生涯最近也挺一帆风顺呢
You know, I'm doing pretty well as an artist myself.
卖了不少我的作品
I've been selling a lot of my stuff.
是吗  没听说过
Really? We hadn't heard.
你要的小蛋糕
And there's your cupcake.
放在"外带"盒子里了  懂意思吧
In case you didn't notice, that container's to go.
懂了
Got it.
他走了  我把他撵走了
He's gone. I got rid of him.
麦克斯
Max?
你在干嘛呢
What are you doing?
捶起司蛋糕
Punching cheesecakes.
你不爽就睡两天  我不爽就捶两个
It's my version of going to bed for two days.
你比较气婚事还是气制服的事啊
Are you more upset about the marriage thing or the uniform thing?
跟他无关  我就气这些起司蛋糕
Oh, this isn't about Johnny. I'm mad at the cheesecakes.
不是应该有樱桃在上面的吗
They were supposed to have cherries on top,
老娘要樱桃
and I wanted cherries!
为什么不是我
Why not me?
好吧  一半是气樱桃  一半气强尼
Okay, maybe it's half no cherries, half Johnny.
我们从没一帆风顺过
Nothing ever does work out for us.
然后听到自己瞎扯的那些
And then I hear myself saying all that ridiculous stuff
跟家政女皇合作的事情
about us talking to Martha Stewart at the gala.
那简直就是痴人说梦嘛
I mean, what was that? It's insane.
是吗
Is it?
说真的  真是痴人说梦吗
Wait, seriously, is it?
还是那其实是大智若愚呢
Or is it just insane enough to be genius?
麦克斯  我们有邀请函  她又会在场
Max, we have the invitation. She'll be there.
我们干嘛浪费时间找保罗啊
Why are we wasting our time with Paul Platt
玛莎才是真正的风云人物
when we can meet the real thing?
带我们最好吃的小蛋糕给玛莎
We can take Martha our best cupcake,
解释我们的情况
explain our situation,
说不定她会愿意给我们个机会
and maybe... maybe she'll talk to us.
她也是一步一步爬上来的嘛
I mean, she was a girl with a dream once, too,
想必她能了解谷底奋战的心情
and she certainly understands hard times.
是要我们去跟踪玛莎·斯图尔特吗
You are talking about us stalking Martha Stewart.
没错  就是这样
I am talking about us stalking Martha Stewart!
我还有个小蛋糕造型的名牌包包
I even have my gorgeous Judith leiber jeweled cupcake purse
来偷带小蛋糕进去  简直是天造地设啊
to smuggle the cupcake in. It's perfect.
把那个包偷出来果然是冥冥中的安排啊
I knew there was a reason I took that from the townhouse.
太好了  我们有蛋糕跟蛋糕包
Great, you have a cupcake and a cupcake purse.
那我们该穿什么去舞会呢  灰姑娘
What else are we gonna wear to the ball, Cinderella?
难道防火巷里的老鼠会帮我们织礼服吗
Are the rats in the alley gonna whip us up some ball gowns?
我们又没有个神仙教母
I mean, it's not exactly like we have a fairy godmother.
姑娘们
Hey, look, girls!
我在我最爱的店里买了皇冠跟魔棒呢
I got myself a crown and a wand at Rhinestoned.
把汤送来我的卡座吧
I'll have the soup in my booth.
反正这估计是我们这辈子
Well, this is as close to a fairytale
最接近美梦成真的时刻了  那就做吧
as you and I are ever gonna get, so what the hell?
麦克斯  就是说我们要想办法混进舞会吗
Max, does that mean we're gonna find a way to go to the ball?
是啊  备妥小蛋糕吧
Oh, yeah. Get your cupcake on,
要开始"混入舞会大作战"啦
'cause we're gonna get balled.